Guide to the Records of Amnesty International of the USA, Inc.
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Executive Director's Files, 1964-1997 bulk 1973-1993
  - Subseries II.3: Jack Healey Files, 1977-1993
    - Fundraising
      - Foundations - General, 1990-1992 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Jack Healey's Arrows Paper--Board of Directors Vision 2000, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 14)
        [restricted until 2023]
      - Foundations, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - "Funds for Freedom", Undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Genocide (Box 21)
      - Genocide Convention--United States Ratification of
        - 1984-1986 (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - 1984-1986 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Lives at Risk: A Study of Violations of Life Integrity in 50 States in 1987. Based on the Amnesty International 1987. Report 1990 March (Box 21, Folder 3)
        (Institute for the Study of Genocide)
    - Growth--Managing Amnesty's Growth: How Do We Do It?, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Hate Speech Task Force, 1991-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
      [restricted until 2024]
    - Haitian Refugee Center v. Gracey, 1985-1985 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      (Amicus Curiae of AIUSA)
    - Homosexuality--Sexual Orientation and the AI Mandate, 1990-1993 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Human Rights Curriculum, 1974-1984 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Human Rights: A Curriculum for Secondary Students, circa 1983 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      (by Jack Randler)
    - Human Rights Education
      - High School Curriculum-International Human Rights, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 11)
        (by Elisabeth T. Dreyfuss)
      - "Human Rights-Education for What?" in Human Rights Quarterly, 1987 August (Box 21, Folder 12)
        (J. Paul Martin)
      - Human Rights Education Task Force, 1986-1989 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Human Rights Now!--World Tour
      - General
        - 1987-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 14-15)
        - 1987-1988, (3 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 1-3)
        - 1988 (Box 22, Folder 4)
          [restricted until 2064]
      - Artwork, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Briefing Book, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Media Strategy and Operations, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - News Clippings, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - 1987 November-1988 December, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Packet, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Preliminary Proposal, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Reebok Human Rights Award, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 4)
        (Booklet)
      - Reebok International, Ltd., 1988 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Religious Packet, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 6)
        (Human Rights Sunday)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) v. Predrag Stevic, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      (AIUSA Brief as Amicus Curiae)
    - Impartiality, 1978-1986 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      (Includes Task Force material)
    - Indigenous Peoples' Task Force, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - International Council Meeting (ICM)--Boston, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      (Originally unfiled material)
    - International Executive Committee (IEC)--AIUSA Report to, 1983-1983 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - International Human Rights Law--Packet, Undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - International Meeting on Military, Economic and Cultural Relations (MEC) and Military, Security and Police Transfers (MSP) (London, UK), 1983 March (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - International Secretariat (IS)
      - Jack Healey and Ann Blyberg's Visit to, 1984 April, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 14-15)
      - List of Weekly Mailings to Sections, 1984-1989, (6 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1-6)
    - Iran Campaign, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Islam and Human Rights, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      (Very small amount of material on the PLO)
    - LeBrun Foundation
      - "Disappeared" Project Grant, 1980-1982 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Medical Exam Project Grant, 1980-1981 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - New York City Office Computerization Grant, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Legal Committee, 1975-1985 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      (Includes Legal Support Network)
    - Legal Support Network (LSN), 1986-1992 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Legislative Coordinators Handbook, 1991 January (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Management Assistance Group (MAG), 1981-1986 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      (Formerly PAMAP)
    - Marley, Bob - Fund, 1990-1992 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Medical Capacity Committee (MCC)
      - 1974-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 25, Folder 2-3)
      - Mailings, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Medical/Health Work, 1981-1985 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Membership--General, 1983-1985 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Membership Communications Task Force, 1990-1993 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Membership Development Task Force, 1986-1993 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Merchandise with a Message, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      (Pamphlet)
    - Mid-Atlantic Region, 1990-1992 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Mid-Atlantic Regional Office, 1987-1989 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Midwest Organizing Project, 1987-January 9 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Midwest Regional Office
      - 1978-1989, (6 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 2-7)
      - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1984-1988 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Midwest Region, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Military, Economic and Cultural Relations (MEC) and Military, Security and Police Transfers (MSP)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - 1983 Background Material, 1983-1992 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Reports, 1992 June (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Minutes/Meetings/Circulars, 1983-1986 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      (Various)
    - Miscellaneous Reading and Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Naked Rights, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      (Theatrical Production presented by AI and Naked Angels; Includes Scripts)
    - National Advisory Council (NAC), 1987 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - National Sections--Annual Reports to the International Executive Committee (IEC), 1987 August 7 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      (AI Index: ORG 01/02/97)
    - National Sector Outreach Program--Proposal, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Northeast Regional Office
      - 1977-1982 (Box 27, Folder 6)
        (Joshua Rubenstein)
      - 1983-1990, (6 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 7-12)
      - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1985-1988 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Northeast Region, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Orientation--A Guide for Holding an Orientation to Amnesty International, circa 1989 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - People of Color Caucus (PCC), 1993 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Personnel Policy Committee (PPC), 1990-1991 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Planning and Priorities Meeting, 1984 May 31 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      (Country Work)
    - Planning Meeting, 1986 April 2 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Political Advisory Task Force, 1985-1986 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      (Includes AIUSA Position Paper,US Human Rights Policy )
    - Political Conventions, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Prisoners of Conscience (POCs)
      - ABC Nightline, 1985-1986 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Letters from Prisoners, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        (Publicity File)
      - Letters from Prisoners Re: Prisoners, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Speaker's List, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Program Review Info, 1991-1993 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Program Unit Meetings, 1982 July (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Public Interest Public Relations (PIPR)--Correspondence Re: Publications and Calendars, 1983-1984 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      (Includes Evaluations)
    - Puerto Rico Groups, 1982-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Reed, Lou - "Voices of Freedom", 1987 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Refugee Coordinators Meeting (Amsterdam), 1986 June 27-29 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Refugee Task Force, 1982-1988 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Refugees
      - 1981-1988 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - AI Program, 1982-1983 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - AIUSA Human Rights Education steering Committee, circa 1992 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        (Includes Resource Curriculum and FORCED OUT Exhibit Information)
      - National Refugee Office AIUSA, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 9)
        (Resource Materials on Refugees and Asylum)
      - Refugees and Immigration, 1977-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
      - Refugees and Immigration, 1977-1984 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Refugees Seeking Asylum, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Regional Action Networks (RANs)
      - 1981-1983 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - A Guide for Groups, circa 1985-1988 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Regional Conferences
      - 1982 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - New England, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Regional and Unit Directors' Meetings, 1983-1988 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Regional Directors' Meeting, 1990 February and September, (2 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 10-11)
    - Regional Membership Coordinators' (RMCs) Meeting (New York City), 1984 January (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Relief
      - 1980-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 13-14)
    - Research, 1983-1984 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Sabbatical--Jack Healey, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Office
      - 1984-1992, (4 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 3-6)
      - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1978-1982 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Scientists in Prison--Cases Under Adoption or Investigation by Amnesty International, circa 1977 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Simple Minds--Tour, 1985-1986 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - South Africa--Chain Letter in Support of the Abolition of Apartheid, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - South Africa Now, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      (Weekly Television Magazine)
    - Southern Office (Regional Office)
      - 1980-1988, (4 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 12-15)
    - Southern Region, 1989-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Special Projects
      - World Tour, 1986-1991 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - 1990-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 4-6)
      - College Rock Tour, 1991-1992 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Concert Proposals for AI's 30th Anniversary Year, 1991-1992 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Country Concert Tour, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Tennis, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - 1992, (3 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 5-7)
      - Haiti Boat People, 1992-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 8-9)
      - Indochine Premiere--Los Angeles, 1992 November 9 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Indochine Premiere--New York, 1992 November 5 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Secret Policeman's Other Ball, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 3)
        (10th Anniversary Reissue)
      - Boston/ICM (International Council Meeting) Donor Reception, 1993 August 5 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - The Song of Jacob Zulu, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Speech Requests, 1990-1993 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Speech Stuff, 1970-1986 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      (Speeches, Material and Clippings)
    - Speeches
      - circa 1982-1988 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1989-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 9-11)
      - Non American Program Bureau (APB)--Correspondence, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Articles Re: Healey Speeches, 1981-1992 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Spin Magazine, 1991-1992 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      (Healey as Guest Editor of November 1991 Issue)
    - Sri Lanka - 1986 Campaign, 1986-1987 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      (Includes Evaluation of)
    - Staff Meetings
      - National Office, 1980-1982 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Western Regional Office (San Francisco), 1981 September 23 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Units/Special, 1981-1983 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Staff Planning Meeting, 1981 July 9 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Strike Force--AIUSA Strike Force Proposal, Undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Student Program, 1987-1992 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Swaziland Mission, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Target Sector Work, 1982-1985 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Task Force and Steering Committees, circa 1987-1992 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Tennis Event, 1991-1992 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Testimonies, 1984-1986, (3 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 1-3)
    - That Was The Week That Was [News Items from the AIUSA Offices], 1989-1993, (4 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 4-7)
    - Things to Do for Jack Healey, 1993 August -September [restricted until 2069] (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Torture, Campaign for the Abolition of (CAT)
      - 1981-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 9-10)
      - Foundation Proposals, 1982-1982 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - 1983 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - 1984 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - 1985 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - The Campaign to Abolish Torture: A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1986 May 1 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Torture - Torture Treatment Centers, 1987-1989 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Trade Unionists, 1976-1983 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Training Program, 1984-1985, (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
    - Training of Trainers Workshop, International--Report, 1986 May 8 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Trautman, Emilie, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      (Financial Crisis at AIUSA)
    - Travel, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      (Jack Healey)
    - United States Government, Task Force on Relations to, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      [restricted until 2016]
    - United States Government Work, 1984-1993 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      (Includes Information on the AIUSA Washington Office)
    - US (United States) Human Rights Policy: An AIUSA Position Paper, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Universal Appeal Campaign for All Prisoners of Conscience (POCs), 1983 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Urgent Action Network
      - Brochures and Guides to Participlan, circa 1980-1984 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Brochures, Fliers and Information Packets, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Position for a Spanish Translator, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - 1985-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 8-9)
      - Liberty Proposal and a Program Review, 1989-1993 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Washington D.C. Office
      - 1977-1985, (3 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 11-13)
      - 1985 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - 1985 (Box 38, Folder 15)
        [restricted until 2061]
      - 1986-1987 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - 1988 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - 1989-1992, (4 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 6-9)
    - West Coast Trips, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Western Regional Office (Los Angeles)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Southwest Regional Coordinator, 1978-1979 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - 1982 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Report: The State of the Programmatic Union, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - General, 1982-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 2-3)
      - Fundraising, 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Press, 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - 1984-1987, (3 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 6-8)
      - 1988 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Western Region
      - 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Women on the Front Line, 1992 September 25, (3 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 4-6)
      (Madrid Concert)
    - Women's Task Force/Women's Campaign, 1989-1991 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Write-a-thon for Human Rights, 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Unfiled Material
      - 1982-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 9-10)
      - 1992-1993 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - circa 1992-1995 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Subseries II.4 William Shulz Files, 1994-1997
    The series currently includes on Schulz's schedule, human rights education, and events. The series is arranged alphabetically.
    - Appointment--New Release Announcing Appointment of, 1994 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Articles By William Schulz, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AI Action Fund--Bylaws, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AIUSA Action Calendar, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - AIUSA Media Spotlight Awards, 1997 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Amnesty Leadership Group, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      (Action Letter)
    - Board of Directors' Memorandum on Organizations Affiliated with AIUSA on and AI's Handling of Country Situations, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Communications Retreat Agenda, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      (Packet)
    - Frontier Trust--Rabbi Trust, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      (Deferred Compensation Plan for Schulz)
    - Human Rights Education Resource Notebooks, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      (Includes Guide to Notebooks and material on the Death Penalty)
    - International Secretariat (IS)--Staff List, 1996 February (Box 1, Folder 11)
      (AI Index: ORG 61/02/96)
    - Long Range Planning Process Report, 1994 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Multiculturalism--Multicultural Development Efforts in AIUSA, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Schedules, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Women--International Women's Day Breakfast at French Embassy, 1994 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Unfiled Material
      (Generally related to scheduling and general issues)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        [restricted until 2071]
  - Subseries II.5: National Section Memos, 1964-1983.
    This series contains memos, background papers, clippings, urgent action newsletters, news releases, reports and other material received from the International Secretariat (IS) and the Research Department. In addition, some files include correspondence related to the National Office of AIUSA. This series is arranged alphabetically by country under the main headings of Africa, Americas, Asia, Europe, and the Middle East and North Africa.
    - AFR 01 Africa--General, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AFR 02 Africa--North Africa--General, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AFR 03 Africa--Southern Africa--General, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AFR 05 Africa--West Africa--Campaign in Francophone West Africa, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - AFR 12 Africa--Angola, 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - AFR 16 Africa--Burundi, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      [restricted until 2049]
    - AFR 17 Africa--Cameroon, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - AFR 17 Africa--Cameroon, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - AFR 19 Africa--Central African Republic, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - AFR 20 Africa--Chad, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - AFR 21 Africa--Comoros, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - AFR 22 Africa--Congo, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - AFR 23 Africa--Djibouti, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - AFR 24 Africa--Equatorial Guinea, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - AFR 25 Africa--Ethiopia, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - AFR 26 Africa--Gabon, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Africa--Gambia, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - AFR 28 Africa--Ghana, 1966-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - AFR 29 Africa--Guinea (Conakry)
      - 1967-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Africa--Ivory Coast, 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - AFR 32 Africa--Kenya, 1966-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - AFR 36 Africa--Malawi
      - 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - AFR 37 Africa--Mali, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - AFR 37 Africa--Morocco, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - AFR 41 Africa--Mozambique, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - AFR 42 Africa--Namibia
      - 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
        [restricted until September 2049]
    - AFR 43 Africa
      - Niger, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Nigeria, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - AFR 46 Africa--Rhodesia/Zimbabwe, 1967-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
    - AFR 48 Africa--Sao Tome and Principe, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - AFR 49 Africa--Senegal, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - AFR 51 Africa--Sierra Leone, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - AFR 52 Africa--Somalia, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - AFR 53 Africa--South Africa
      - 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - AFR 54 Africa--Sudan, 1972-1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - AFR 55 Africa--Swaziland, 1979-1979 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - AFR 56 Africa--Tanzania, 1967-1977 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - AFR 57 Africa--Togo, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - AFR 58 Africa--Tunisia, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - AFR 59 Africa--Uganda, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - AFR 62 Africa--Zaire, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - AFR 63 Africa--Zambia, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - AMR 02 Americas--Central America--General, 1976-1980. 1983, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - AMR 03 Americas--South America--General, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - AMR 13 Americas--Argentina
      - 1972-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
      - Talamante, Olga--Affadavit and Complaint, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Palma, Daniel, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - 1979-1980, (3 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
      - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - AMR 15 Americas--Barbados, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - AMR 18 Americas--Bolivia
      - 1967-1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - AMR 19 Americas--Brazil (Box 3)
      - 1967-1972, (3 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
      - Report on Torture, 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - 1973-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
      - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 1975-1980, (3 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 8-10)
    - AMR 20 Americas--Canada, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - AMR 22 Americas--Chile
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Case Sheets from Rose Styron, 1975-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1976-1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1977-1980, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
    - AMR 23 Americas--Columbia, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - AMR 24 Americas--Costa Rica, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - AMR 25 Americas--Cuba
      - 1966-1983, (3 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 7-9)
      - 1980-1983 [restricted until 2058] (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - AMR 27 Americas--Dominican Republic, 1972-1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - AMR 28 Americas--Ecuador, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - AMR 29 Americas--El Salvador
      - 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Archbishop Oscar Romero Correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - AMR 34 Americas--Guatemala
      - 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - 1975-1979, (4 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - AMR 36 Americas--Haiti
      - 1966-1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1966-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - AMR 37 Americas--Honduras, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - AMR 38 Americas--Jamaica, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - AMR 41 Americas--Mexico, 1964-1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - AMR 43 Americas--Nicaragua, 1967-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - AMR 45 Americas--Paraguay
      - 1970-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
      - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - AMR 46 Americas--Peru
      - 1966-1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - AMR 59 Americas--St. Kitts-Nevis, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - AMR 49 Americas--Trinidad, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - AMR 51 Americas--United States
      - 1967-1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Charlotte 3, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Grant, Jim (POC), 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 22)
        (Grant's Articles from the Southern Patriot )
      - Johnson, Lee Otis, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        (Behavior Modification Techniques; American Refugee Project)
      - Obadele, Imari A. (Richard B. Henry), 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Prison Conditions, 1969-1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Prison Conditions, 1969-1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - AMR 52 Americas--Uruguay
      - 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Press and Mailings, circa 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - 1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - 1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - AMR 53 Americas--Venezuela, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)